In Ghana, sadly, countless children are
abandoned and fall victim to being
captured as slaves to the fishing
industry. And after speaking with
countless locals, I came to the
heartbreaking realization that being
rescued is only the beginning of their
struggle. Even for those fortunate
enough to escape, years of relentless
abuse and exploitation have left them in
desperate need of medical care. Yet,
there are no adequate facilities to
provide the treatment they so urgently
require. So, we made it our mission to
build a brand new surgical center in the
heart of Ghana to combat the lack of
medical care to help survivors like
these two brothers, Ernest and Richmond,
who were sold as slaves after being
abandoned by their parents and only
rescued at the age of 16. When our mom
and dad give birth to us, we don't fight
them and they leave us. As slaves of the
fishing industry, the two were separated
and had to survive on their own, not
knowing if they will ever see each other
again. Sometimes they will try to push
you inside the water. If you don't know
how to swim, then you are going to die.
20 of my friends, they all die.
But luckily, the two brothers were
rescued by the Ghana Make a Difference
Foundation, also known as GMAD, an
organization that combats child slavery
here in Ghana. I was very happy that I
come to GMAD because what they have done
to me, I'm appreciate of that. As it
stands, GMAD serves as a shelter for
these abused and orphaned children by
breaking the chains of their past and
providing them a life of love and care.
The goal is to rehabilitate and educate
them so that when they grow out of
adolescence, they are capable of making
a new life for themselves. When the
brothers were saved, they luckily did
not need any medical attention, but this
was not the case for many of their
peers. So, to find out more, I met up
with Austin, the executive director of
GMAD, who explained the issue with
medical care for the survivors that need
it. They have to travel to an
overcrowded hospital 30 minutes away
from the GMAD compound and wait in long
lines of over 600 people. The
bottleneck's always been O space. We've
never had enough O space. You know, the
volunteer surgeons here will perform
over 200 major medical operations in 4
and 1/2 days. After seeing so many
people wait in line the whole day only
to be denied treatment, we immediately
began the construction of a new surgical
center in the GMAD
compound. While the project was
underway, I spent more time with the
kids and got to see the abundance of
life here at the compound.
[Music]
I'm so happy I met Mr.
I was just in shock, but luckily I met a
celebrity here one day.
The kids that come here to gone to make
a difference, they own their stories and
it's really powerful because of what
they've went through and what they've
overcome. Seeing all the warm smiles on
each of these children's faces, one
could never have guessed that they come
from such devastating backgrounds. If it
wasn't for Cory and Stacy Hoffman, who
founded GMAD 12 years ago, none of this
would have been possible. When we first
came to Ghana, we realized that there
were so many children that had no one to
advocate for them. Children need
families to thrive. As the construction
of the surgical center was nearly
complete, we sat down with some of the
volunteer surgeons to hear more about
their experiences. I think yesterday
when we showed up, we had probably
around 600 people here begging to be
seen. And so, it only takes one time to
see that and to not come back. The
doctors and surgeons that volunteer to
help here often see cases that are so
severe they've literally never seen it
before in their entire career. You see,
you know, we have 60 individuals here
that are volunteering their time. They
pay their own way. They come back and
they want to come back because they feed
off the energy of the people and the the
manner in which they are so resilient
and they overcome. That's what's
infectious is watching the people just
deal with the hand they've been dealt
and and make the best of it. So, after
months of construction, we had finally
finished building GMAD's new surgical
center, and it was now time for the big
reveal. In the name of Almighty
God, the Son, the Holy Spirit. Amen.
With this new surgical center, GMAD will
now be able to provide treatment to more
children and families of the surrounding
community. Now, we have the ability to
perform surgeries to folks that need it.
[Music]
After the grand opening, the folks at
GMAT held a celebration outside their
newly built surgical center. And the
very next night, they were able to save
one of the very first patients to be
treated in this facility, a young girl
named Mary, whose legs were so deformed
that she could barely walk. But luckily
for her, the New Beast Philanthropy
Surgical Center provided the surgeons an
adequate facility where they could fix
her legs. Mary will be one of many whose
lives will change for the better now
that the surgeons at GMAD have more
capacity to help others. If you'd like
to be a part of the incredible work that
GMAD is doing, I need you to click the
link in description and donate right
now. Seriously, with your support, GMAD
will be able to get more kids out of
slavery and provide them with the love
and care they deserve. Go away, Wasp.
I'm trying to help people. You should
consider it. It would mean a lot to
them, and it would honestly mean a lot
to me. I also want to say a special
thanks to Ox Blue for donating the
time-lapse cameras we used in this
video. You guys are awesome.